



# **Guilherme Morone Araujo**

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/guimorone

**Gender:** Male **Date of birth:** 10/02/2001 **Nationality:** Brazilian

#### **ABOUT ME**

Originally from Rio but now based in Recife, I've had the privilege of growing up in two vibrant cities. My passions are as diverse as my background, ranging from an avid love for games and books to an insatiable curiosity for travel and technology. Furthermore, I am always eager to explore new opportunities and challenges that can help me grow both as a professional and as a person, fuelled by my passion for learning and applying new technologies to solve real-world problems.

I have been working on Software Development since 2020, and I am used to developing Big Data applications that demand high efficiency, scalability, and low cost. All my projects demanded skills in web development, data engineering, CI/CD, Docker, GitHub Actions, and cloud computing, in order to deliver quality solutions to clients.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### [ 10/04/2024 - Current ] **Software Engineer**

Neurotech https://www.neurotech.com.br

City: Recife | Country: Brazil | Email address: guilherme.morone@neurotech.com.br | Name of unit or department: Hydra - Neurolake

Full-time job:

- In general, using skills in software, data engineering and backend development with Python, FastAPI, Terraform, Git, Airflow, Bash and cloud computing on AWS.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to achieve project goals.
- Ensure high-quality, scalable application development.
- Using AWS solutions such as Lambda, DynamoDB, EC2, Athena, S3, Step Functions and more.
- Extract data from different sources and make it available for many users in a data lake.

[ 03/09/2024 - 09/10/2024 ] **Full Stack Developer** 

GPC Gestão https://gpcgestao.com.br

City: Recife | Country: Brazil

Freelancer:

• Built an admin website using React with TypeScript and Tailwind CSS.

#### [ 10/04/2024 - 31/05/2024 ]

#### **Software Engineer**

https://jalan.com.br Ialan

City: Recife | Country: Brazil

Full-time job:

· Worked as a Full Stack developer using Vue.js and Quasar along with Python and Lambda Functions (AWS).

#### [ 01/03/2024 – 31/03/2024 ]

#### **Mobile Engineer**

aca.so https://aca.so

City: Recife | Country: Brazil

Freelancer:

• Worked as a Mobile Engineer in a project (aca.so mobile app) using React Native.

### [ 01/07/2023 - 28/12/2023 ] Full Stack Developer

City: Recife | Country: Brazil

Freelancer:

- Website made with 3 more colleagues to an external customer.
- The main purpose is to identify bank check fields easily, so you do not have to type manually.

- The bank check OCR is based on our customer's API, we did not implement it, just the website
- It also offers API Integration, history download and other features.
- Developed using React, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS and Django (Python).

#### [ 01/02/2022 - 28/12/2023 ] **Software Engineer**

Oncase https://www.oncase.com.br

City: Recife | Country: Brazil

Full-time job:

- Developed Big Data applications with a focus on high efficiency, scalability, and low cost.
- · Developed frontend applications using React (JavaScript, TypeScript and HTML/CSS) and Redux.
- Implemented backend functionality using Python frameworks Flask and Django.
- Implemented effective CI/CD pipelines for seamless integration and deployment through Docker and GitHub Actions.
- In general, utilized skills in web development (Django, React and HTML/CSS), data engineering, CI/CD, Docker, GitHub Actions, and cloud computing.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to achieve project goals.
- Enhanced customer relationships through the delivery of top-notch solutions.
- Ensured high-quality and scalable application development.
- Hosted applications on Google Cloud Platform using Cloud Run and Artifact Registry.
- · Utilized Amazon Web Services for hosting, leveraging services like Amplify, Route53, and Lambda.

#### [ 01/08/2022 - 31/10/2022 ] **Mobile Engineer**

InSpace https://inspace.tech City: Recife | Country: Brazil

Freelancer:

• I have worked with the identification of objects (censored specificity) from a mobile camera for legal purposes.

### [ 01/05/2020 - 30/12/2020 ]

#### **Game Developer**

**Educandus** https://educandus.com.br

City: Recife | Country: Brazil

Internship:

• I have worked as a game developer using Construct 3 software and JavaScript, building educational games for students from preschool to high school levels.

#### [ 01/06/2021 - 31/10/2021 ] **Game Developer**

**Educandus** https://educandus.com.br

City: Recife | Country: Brazil

Internship:

• I have worked as a game developer using Construct 3 software and JavaScript, building educational games for students from preschool to high school levels.

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

## [ 01/02/2019 – 31/08/2024 ]

## **Bachelor in Computer Engineering**

Federal University of Pernambuco (UFPE) https://portal.cin.ufpe.br

**City:** Recife | **Country:** Brazil | **Field(s) of study:** Information and Communication Technologies: Software and applications development and analysis
Computer use
Database and network design and administration • Information and communication technologies not elsewhere classified • In formation and Communication Technologies (ICTs) not further defined; Engineering, manufacturing and construction: • Electronics and automation | Final grade: 9.02/10.0 | Level in EQF: EQF level 6

Link: https://repositorio.ufpe.br/handle/123456789/58235

### [ 01/06/2022 - 31/03/2024 ] **Student Teaching Assistant**

Federal University of Pernambuco (UFPE) https://portal.cin.ufpe.br

Field(s) of study: Information and Communication Technologies: • Software and applications development and analysis

- Dedicated Student Teaching Assistant in the field of Software and Systems Engineering.
- · Provided invaluable support to students in software development and requirements engineering, with a primary goal of crafting top-tier applications of exceptional quality.

## [ 07/11/2024 - 12/11/2024 ] **GraphQL by Example**

Udemy https://udemy.com

Link: https://ude.my/UC-2f72d8c0-5e8c-4c08-a657-cb379948c6f1

## [ 01/11/2024 - 07/11/2024 ] The Complete Cyber Security Course - Volume 1: Hackers Exposed!

Udemy https://udemy.com

Link: https://ude.my/UC-1acdc51c-9652-40d8-80af-24d65aa27727

[ 15/03/2024 – 03/04/2024 ]

## The Complete Flutter Development Bootcamp with Dart

Udemy https://udemy.com

**Link:** https://ude.my/UC-3fd9599a-bff2-4960-8d34-dbb3b41ced55

## [ 01/03/2023 - 14/03/2023 ] Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Data, ML, and AI in Google Cloud - Locales

Google Cloud Skills Boost https://www.cloudskillsboost.google

Link: https://www.cloudskillsboost.google/public\_profiles/d8f54101-4f80-4aee-8e46-2320e3e20646/

badges/3311200

[ 01/03/2023 - 13/03/2023 ]

## Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Infrastructure in Google Cloud - Locales

Google Cloud Skills Boost https://www.cloudskillsboost.google

Link: https://www.cloudskillsboost.google/public\_profiles/d8f54101-4f80-4aee-8e46-2320e3e20646/

badges/3303084

[ 01/03/2023 - 13/03/2023 ]

#### Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Networking & Security - Locales

Google Cloud Skills Boost https://www.cloudskillsboost.google

Link: https://www.cloudskillsboost.google/public\_profiles/d8f54101-4f80-4aee-8e46-2320e3e20646/

badges/3305980

[ 01/03/2023 - 12/03/2023 ]

### Google Cloud Computing Foundations: Cloud Computing Fundamentals - Locales

Google Cloud Skills Boost https://www.cloudskillsboost.google

Link: https://www.cloudskillsboost.google/public\_profiles/d8f54101-4f80-4aee-8e46-2320e3e20646/

badges/3302433

[ 01/04/2020 - 21/04/2020 ]

### The Complete 2020 Web Development Bootcamp

Udemy https://udemy.com

Link: https://ude.my/UC-5d594204-a414-4cb1-a388-72e3daf7c1c6

#### LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Portuguese

Other language(s):

**English** 

LISTENING C1 READING C2 WRITING C2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

German

LISTENING A2 READING A2 WRITING A2

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION A2 SPOKEN INTERACTION A2** 

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user